

CONTACT ME



+491621944656



ivoltovp@gmail.com



Munich, Germany



www.linkedin.com/in/ilya-voltov-b44b49207

EDUCATION

master

Saint-Petersburg State University of Economics, Saint-Petersburg

Thesis: "Economic and statistical analysis of energy efficiency in the regions of the Russian Federation"

2008 - 2013

PhD of economics

Peter the Great Saint-Petersburg Polytechnic University, Saint-Petersburg

Research topic: "<u>Data Mining</u> for the Probability Prediction of the Power Grid Facilities Outages"

constantly take courses on stepik.org and kaggle.com

SKILLS

- Python (Pandas, Numpy, Plotly, Matplotlib)
- JavaScript (MUI framework)
- Jupyter; Google Colab
- PostgreSQL; ClickHouse
- · Heroku; Yandex.Cloud
- English B2

llia Voltov

Data Analyst

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly motivated and responsible professional with 10 years of experience in data analysis. Constantly staying on top of data science trends and techniques.

Now I'm looking for a new challenge for myself - as working with data is my passion and I want to keep improving.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Data Analyst

01.2023 - now

GlowByte Consulting (developing data-driven solutions), Munich, remote

Responsibilities:

- Identify the business question (negotiations with customers)
- Collect, clean and analyze the data (development of hypotheses and models)
- Development of analytical reports based on the developed models Achievements:

Development of several models for predicting the buying of insurance policies

Head of Software Development

2018 - 01.2023

PJSC "Federal Testing Center" (PJSC ROSSETI - the largest electric power company in Russia), hybrid

Responsibilities:

- Managing and mentoring a team of 10 developers and analysts
- Applying Agile (scrum/kanban)
- Creating roadmaps and user-stories for the projects
- Developing systems and algorithms to efficiently export data and present it to stakeholders

Achievements:

"Information system for determining imbalances in the distribution network, their interpretation and calculation of a probabilistic model of unaccounted or non-contractual consumption of electric energy (ISON)"

forecasting system, machine learning algorithms (patent number $\underline{2021662181}$) position: leader of the project

developed and implemented machine learning models

Data Analyst

2014 - 2018

PJSC "Rosseti Lenergo" (PJSC ROSSETI - the largest electric power company in Russia), on-site

Responsibilities:

- Analyzed data independently to deliver insights about operational performance and proactively drove improvements
- Effectively planned and collaborated with a large team on data driven initiatives to solve complex operational problems
- Developed statistical techniques and used machine learning to solve problems
- Created end-to-end data pipeline from data warehouse to BI report

Achievements

Business intelligence systems based on Power BI analytics, building dashboards

position: analyst, programmer

developed and implemented analytical dashboards (interactive reports)